<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?> <rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://www.nasa.gov/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"> <channel> <title>NASA Image of the Day</title>
 <description>The latest NASA &quot;Image of the Day&quot; image.</description>
 <link>http://www.nasa.gov/</link>
 <atom:link rel="self" href="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss" />
 <language>en-us</language>
 <managingEditor>yvette.smith-1@nasa.gov</managingEditor>
 <webMaster>brian.dunbar@nasa.gov</webMaster>
 <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
 <item> <title>The Shocking Behavior of a Speedy Star</title>
 <link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/the-shocking-behavior-of-a-speedy-star</link>
 <description>Roguish runaway stars can have a big impact on their surroundings as they plunge through the Milky Way galaxy. Their high-speed encounters shock the galaxy, creating arcs, as seen in this newly released image from NASA’s Spitzer Space Telescope.
In this case, the speedster star is known as Kappa Cassiopeiae, or HD 2905 to astronomers. It is a massive, hot supergiant moving at around 2.5 million mph relative to its neighbors (1,100 kilometers per second). But what really makes the star stand out in this image is the surrounding, streaky red glow of material in its path. Such structures are called bow shocks, and they can often be seen in front of the fastest, most massive stars in the galaxy.
Bow shocks form where the magnetic fields and wind of particles flowing off a star collide with the diffuse, and usually invisible, gas and dust that fill the space between stars. How these shocks light up tells astronomers about the conditions around the star and in space. Slow-moving stars like our sun have bow shocks that are nearly invisible at all wavelengths of light, but fast stars like Kappa Cassiopeiae create shocks that can be seen by Spitzer’s infrared detectors.
&gt; More information</description>
 <enclosure url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/pia17843bowshock_0_0.jpg?itok=Qv5sxuAt" length="4068975" type="image/jpeg" />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/the-shocking-behavior-of-a-speedy-star</guid>
 <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2014 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
 <source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
</item>
 <item> <title>Astronaut John H. Glenn Jr. With Mercury &quot;Friendship 7&quot; Spacecraft</title>
 <link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/astronaut-john-h-glenn-jr-with-mercury-friendship-7-spacecraft</link>
 <description>Astronaut John H. Glenn Jr., pilot of the Mercury Atlas 6 (MA-6) spaceflight, poses for a photo with the Mercury &quot;Friendship 7&quot; spacecraft during preflight activities. On Feb. 20, 1962, Glenn piloted the Mercury-Atlas 6 &quot;Friendship 7&quot; spacecraft on the first manned orbital mission of the United States. Launched from Kennedy Space Center, Fla., he completed a successful three-orbit mission around the earth, reaching a maximum altitude (apogee) of approximately 162 statute miles and an orbital velocity of approximately 17,500 miles per hour. Glenn&#039;s &quot;Friendship 7&quot; Mercury spacecraft landed approximately 800 miles southeast of KSC in the vicinity of Grand Turk Island. Mission duration from launch to impact was 4 hours, 55 minutes, and 23 seconds.
Image Credit: NASA</description>
 <enclosure url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/62ma6-55.jpg?itok=4XvNqgl2" length="2739690" type="image/jpeg" />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/astronaut-john-h-glenn-jr-with-mercury-friendship-7-spacecraft</guid>
 <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
 <source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
</item>
 <item> <title>Martian Dunes Flying in Formation</title>
 <link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/martian-dunes-flying-in-formation</link>
 <description>Migratory birds and military aircraft often fly in a V-shaped formation. The “V” formation greatly boosts the efficiency and range of flying birds, because all except the first fly in the upward motion of air -- called upwash -- from the wingtip vortices of the bird ahead.
In this image of a dune field on Mars in a large crater near Mawrth Vallis, some of the dunes appear to be in a V-shaped formation. For dune fields, the spacing of individual dunes is a function of sand supply, wind speed, and topography.
This image was acquired by the HiRISE camera aboard NASA&#039;s Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter on Dec. 30, 2013. The University of Arizona, Tucson, operates the HiRISE camera, which was built by Ball Aerospace &amp; Technologies Corp., Boulder, Colo. NASA&#039;s Jet Propulsion Laboratory, a division of the California Institute of Technology in Pasadena, manages the Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter Project for the NASA Science Mission Directorate, Washington.
&gt; More information and image products
Image Credit: NASA/JPL-Caltech/Univ. of Arizona
	Caption: Alfred McEwen</description>
 <enclosure url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/pia17981.jpg?itok=GAMRUzpZ" length="797802" type="image/jpeg" />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/martian-dunes-flying-in-formation</guid>
 <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
 <source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
</item>
 <item> <title>Coronal Loops in an Active Region of the Sun</title>
 <link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/coronal-loops-in-an-active-region-of-the-sun</link>
 <description>An active region of the sun just rotating into the view of NASA&#039;s Solar Dynamics Observatory gives a profile view of coronal loops over about a two-day period, from Feb. 8-10, 2014. Coronal loops are found around sunspots and in active regions. These structures are associated with the closed magnetic field lines that connect magnetic regions on the solar surface. Many coronal loops last for days or weeks, but most change quite rapidly. This image was taken in extreme ultraviolet light.
&gt; View associated video
Image Credit: NASA/Solar Dynamics Observatory</description>
 <enclosure url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/festooningloops.jpg?itok=qo4C6-MN" length="143579" type="image/jpeg" />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/coronal-loops-in-an-active-region-of-the-sun</guid>
 <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2014 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
 <source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
</item>
 <item> <title>Chandra Observatory Sees a Heart in the Darkness</title>
 <link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/chandra-observatory-sees-a-heart-in-the-darkness</link>
 <description>This Chandra X-Ray Observatory image of the young star cluster NGC 346 highlights a heart-shaped cloud of 8 million-degree Celsius gas in the central region. Evidence from radio, optical and ultraviolet telescopes suggests that the hot cloud, which is about 100 light years across, is the remnant of a supernova explosion that occurred thousands of years ago.
The progenitor could have been a companion of the massive young star that is responsible for the bright X-ray source at the top center of the image. This young star, HD 5980, one of the most massive known, has been observed to undergo dramatic eruptions during the last decade. An alternative model for the origin of the hot cloud is that eruptions of HD 5980 long ago produced the cloud of hot gas, in a manner similar to the gas cloud observed around the massive star Eta Carinae. Future observations will be needed to decide between the alternatives. Until then, the nature of the heart in the darkness will remain mysterious.
&gt; View original image
	&gt; More about Chandra
Image Credit: NASA/CXC/U.Liege/Y.Nazé et al.</description>
 <enclosure url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/12437854453_f256508925_o.jpg?itok=JnbHOkAE" length="64955" type="image/jpeg" />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/chandra-observatory-sees-a-heart-in-the-darkness</guid>
 <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2014 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
 <source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
</item>
 <item> <title>Crawler-Transporter Passes Milestone Test at NASA&#039;s Kennedy Space Center</title>
 <link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/crawler-transporter-passes-milestone-test-at-nasas-kennedy-space-center</link>
 <description>The crawler-transporter that will carry NASA’s Space Launch System (SLS) and Orion spacecraft to Launch Pad 39B for launch on Exploration Mission-1 in 2017 recently passed the first phase of an important milestone test at Kennedy Space Center in Florida. The Ground Systems Development and Operations Program completed testing of new traction roller bearings on crawler-transporter 2 (CT-2), on two of the massive vehicle’s truck sections, A and C, in late January. The new roller bearing assemblies that were installed on one side of the crawler are visible in this Jan. 31, 2014 image. CT-2 returned to the Vehicle Assembly Building (VAB) at Kennedy Space Center, where work continues to install new roller bearing assemblies on the B and D truck sections.
For more than 45 years the crawler-transporters were used to transport the mobile launcher platform and the Apollo-Saturn V rockets and, later, space shuttles to Launch Pads 39A and B. Upgrades to CT-2 are necessary in order to increase the lifted-load capacity from 12 million to 18 million pounds to support the weight of the mobile launcher and future launch vehicles, including the SLS and Orion.
&gt; Read more
Photo credit: NASA/Kim Shiflett</description>
 <enclosure url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/2014-1314.jpg?itok=6PSUVL0H" length="5044618" type="image/jpeg" />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/crawler-transporter-passes-milestone-test-at-nasas-kennedy-space-center</guid>
 <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
 <source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
</item>
 <item> <title>Set of NanoRacks CubeSats Deployed From International Space Station</title>
 <link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/set-of-nanoracks-cubesats-deployed-from-space-station</link>
 <description>ISS038-E-045009 (11 Feb. 2014) --- The Small Satellite Orbital Deployer (SSOD), in the grasp of the Kibo laboratory robotic arm, is photographed by an Expedition 38 crew member on the International Space Station as it deploys a set of NanoRacks CubeSats. The CubeSats program contains a variety of experiments such as Earth observations and advanced electronics testing. Station solar array panels, Earth’s horizon and the blackness of space provide the backdrop for the scene.
&gt; Read More: CubeSat Work Proceeds as Crew Landing Moves Up a Day
Image Credit: NASA</description>
 <enclosure url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/iss038e045009.jpg?itok=T6oTKZrK" length="1496049" type="image/jpeg" />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/set-of-nanoracks-cubesats-deployed-from-space-station</guid>
 <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2014 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
 <source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
</item>
 <item> <title>Landsat 8&#039;s First Year</title>
 <link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/landsat-8s-first-year</link>
 <description>On Feb. 11, 2013, the Landsat 8 satellite rocketed into a sunny California morning onboard a powerful Atlas V and began its life in orbit. In the year since launch, scientists have been working to understand the information the satellite has been sending back. Some have been calibrating the data—checking it against ground observations and matching it to the rest of the 42-year-long Landsat record. At the same time, the broader science community has been learning to use the new data.
The map above—one of the first complete views of the United States from Landsat 8—is an example of how scientists are testing Landsat 8 data. David Roy, a co-leader of the USGS-NASA Landsat science team and researcher at South Dakota State University, made the map with observations taken during August 2013 by the satellite’s Operational Land Imager.
The strips in the image above are a result of the way Landsat 8 operates. Like its predecessors, Landsat 8 collects data in 185-kilometer (115-mile) wide strips called swaths or paths. Each orbit follows a predetermined ground track so that the same path is imaged each time an orbit is repeated. It takes 233 paths and 16 days to cover all of the land on Earth. This means that every land surface has the potential to be imaged once every 16 days, giving Roy two or three opportunities to get a cloud-free view of each pixel in the United States in a month.
Image Credit: NASA/David Roy</description>
 <enclosure url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/usa_oli_201308_lrg.jpg?itok=RZpyAy6G" length="60237979" type="image/jpeg" />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/landsat-8s-first-year</guid>
 <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2014 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
 <source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
</item>
 <item> <title>Solar Array Panels on Russian Segment of Space Station</title>
 <link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/solar-array-panels-on-russian-segment-of-station</link>
 <description>ISS038-E-042665 (5 Feb. 2014) --- Solar array panels on the Russian segment of the International Space Station and a blue and white part of Earth are photographed by an Expedition 38 crew member while the crew watches for the arrival of the ISS Progress 54 cargo spacecraft, loaded with 2.8 tons of food, fuel and supplies for the station crew. The new Progress, which docked to the station at 5:22 p.m. EST on Wednesday, Feb. 5, is loaded with 1,764 pounds of propellant, 110 pounds of oxygen, 926 pounds of water and 2,897 pounds of spare parts, experiment hardware and other supplies. Progress 54 is slated to spend about two months docked to the complex before departing to make way for ISS Progress 55.
Image Credit: NASA</description>
 <enclosure url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/iss038e042665.jpg?itok=zIPSnRGR" length="1527880" type="image/jpeg" />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/solar-array-panels-on-russian-segment-of-station</guid>
 <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2014 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
 <source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
</item>
 <item> <title>Sochi, Russia Winter Olympic Sites (Mountain Cluster)</title>
 <link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/sochi-russia-winter-olympic-sites-mountain-cluster</link>
 <description>The 2014 Winter Olympic ski runs may be rated double black diamond, but they&#039;re not quite as steep as they appear in this image of the skiing and snowboarding sites for the Sochi Winter Olympic Games, acquired on Jan. 4, 2014, by the Advanced Spaceborne Thermal Emission and Reflection Radiometer (ASTER) instrument on NASA&#039;s Terra spacecraft. Rosa Khutar ski resort near Sochi, Russia, is in the valley at center, and the runs are visible on the shadowed slopes on the left-hand side of the valley. Height has been exaggerated 1.5 times to bring out topographic details. The games, which begin on Feb. 7 and continue for 17 days, feature six new skiing and boarding events plus the return of the legendary Jamaican bobsled team to the winter games for the first time since 2002.
In this southwest-looking image, red indicates vegetation, white is snow, and the resort site appears in gray. The area imaged is about 11 miles (18 kilometers) across in the foreground and 20 miles (32 kilometers) from front to back. The image was created from the ASTER visible and near-infrared bands, draped over ASTER-derived digital elevation data.
With its 14 spectral bands from the visible to the thermal infrared wavelength region and its high spatial resolution of 15 to 90 meters (about 50 to 300 feet), ASTER images Earth to map and monitor the changing surface of our planet. ASTER is one of five Earth-observing instruments launched Dec. 18, 1999, on Terra. The instrument was built by Japan&#039;s Ministry of Economy, Trade and Industry. A joint U.S./Japan science team is responsible for validation and calibration of the instrument and data products.
The broad spectral coverage and high spectral resolution of ASTER provides scientists in numerous disciplines with critical information for surface mapping and monitoring of dynamic conditions and temporal change. Example applications are: monitoring glacial advances and retreats; monitoring potentially active volcanoes; identifying crop stress; determining cloud morphology and physical properties; wetlands evaluation; thermal pollution monitoring; coral reef degradation; surface temperature mapping of soils and geology; and measuring surface heat balance.
The U.S. science team is located at NASA&#039;s Jet Propulsion Laboratory, Pasadena, Calif. The Terra mission is part of NASA&#039;s Science Mission Directorate, Washington, D.C. ;More information about ASTER is available at asterweb.jpl.nasa.gov/.
Image Credit: NASA/GSFC/METI/ERSDAC/JAROS, and U.S./Japan ASTER Science Team</description>
 <enclosure url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/12350435303_5849b2443a_o.jpg?itok=9ejlSlVb" length="448926" type="image/jpeg" />
 <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/sochi-russia-winter-olympic-sites-mountain-cluster</guid>
 <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
 <source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
